

W: linkedin.com/in/zunaib-imtiaz/

E: zunaib60@gmail.com

P: +92 308 4225537

L: Johar Town, Lahore, Pakistan

## **PERSONAL INFO**

Software Engineer with 2 plus years of Full Stack Development experience developing projects from diverse domains. Currently working as a full stack developer in Pakistan's leading AI Organization Afiniti across diverse technologies. Got experience in developing fast and responsive user interfaces with modular application servers. My strongest suit is pixel perfect user interface development. Love learning new things and tools every day. Driven individual with the ability to adapt to any situation and potential to grow self and others.



# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### LEAD FULL STACK DEVELOPER

AFINITI – PAIR BETTER. | MAY 2019 - PRESENT

At **Afiniti**, started as an Analyst Software Engineer, initially worked on the user interface development part of an application and later on moved to full stack development. Working excellently for 10 months got me promoted to Software Engineer and started working on full stack applications, building the whole application from scratch to deployments, developing services and training junior employees. Worked on projects from diversified domains performing following duties,

- Developed fast, reliable, responsive and flexible user interfaces using ReactJS, NextJS with ES6 to get a fluid visual appearance that attracted a lot more users and improved user experience.
- Developed user interfaces for multiple devices considering specific layout, cross browser compatibility and useability using SCSS grids / breakpoints and ReactJS Hooks to attain multi device support that catered a more diverse range of users.
- Integrated global state managing technologies like Redux to cater the global usage of information all across the application that made data management easier to handle.
- Developed a custom ReactJS component library for Afinitiusing ReactJS, SCSS, Storybook and deployed it to Afiniti's NPM Proxy for the whole organization to build user interfaces.
- Acquired hands on experience with 3rd party UI Libraries integration like Antd, Chakra UI, Material UI and more UI Libraries to get a much faster development pace.
- Developed Complex Dynamic Forms and used UseForm and Formik like 3rd party npm packages so that a lot of data can be handled and validated in an organized way.
- Developed scalable and modular Application Servers using NodeJS, Python Flask and Hasura so that it can be attached to any frontend library or framework with
- Developed high end performance APIs using Redis to cater load balancing of increasing requests per second that resulted in faster response times.
- Developed API Middleware Services using NodeJS to cater a higher order functionality for every API call.
- Deployed Full Stack Applications using Nginx, Docker and GitHub to make the application go live and be interactable.
- Worked on Integrating new features into Legacy Projects so that legacy projects are also being maintained.

 Worked on Production Bugs and Issues to keep up the client satisfaction and a bug free application.

### FULL STACK FREELANCING SERVICE

UPWORK. | JUN 2020 - PRESENT

Working on **Upwork**, dealt with projects from diverse domains and technologies. Encountered issues and obstacles out of an organizational environment on Upwork which had let me to grow personally and professionally improving customer experience and my technical skills. While being a Freelancer, following duties were performed,

- Developed Client websites using ReactJS, NodeJS, SCSS, MongoDB with custom client-oriented functionalities to achieve excellent performance and best possible visual appearance with good code practices.
- Converted PSD Designs into ReactJS Pages with pixel perfect designs and accurate color schemes to reflect a visual idea into a visual product.
- Worked on Shopify to develop websites, integrated Vanilla JavaScript and SCSS into Shopify for custom features so that some not out of the box functionalities could be achieved.
- Deployed Websites to custom domains using GitHub Pages, Nginx and Docker to make them interactable.
- Attained 100 percent Client satisfaction with my fast response and revisions.



## **EDUCATION**

## **BACHELOR IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING** COMSATS, LAHORE

BACHELOR DEGREE | SEP 2015 - JUN 2019

## INTERMEDIATE IN PRE-ENGINEERING GOVT. SCIENCE COLLEGE, LAHORE

INTERMEDIATE DEGREE | SEP 2013 - JUN 2015



# **SKILLS**

- ReactJS
- NextJS
- JavaScript
- ES6
- TypeScript
- HTML 5/CSS 3
- SCSS / Theming

- Storybook
- NodeJS
- Python
- Hasura
- MongoDB
- MySQL
- PhpMvAdmin

- Docker
- Nginx
- Git Versioning
- Bitbucket
- JIRA
- Confluence

Additionally, worked in numerous other languages too,

- Worked on NumPy, Tensor-flow, Keras, Open-CV, Nvidia CUDA for Machine learning development.
- Worked on Back-end Technologies like GraphQL and Python Flask.
- Worked on Custom Styling with SCSS, Mix-ins, Variables and Media Queries.
- Worked on building Storybook from scratch and modifying it to my needs.
- Worked for community, answering community questions on stack overflow too.

## PROJECTS

### 01. CFI REVIEW

www.cfireview.com | 2020

CFIReview is a Review Website for Flying Instructors, developed this website for an Upwork client, who wanted custom designs and a fully responsive site. This site was

developed using ReactJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, SCSS, Ant Design and some 3rd party npm packages.

#### 02. OUR FAMILYTALES

www.ourfamilytales.com | 2021

Our Family Tales is a Story Telling Website, developed this site for an Upwork client too, she wanted a fully customizable questionnaire built into a new Shopify store, did both to those things using some of shopify's built-in functionalities, Vanilla JavaScript and SCSS.

#### 03. AIROKIT

Airokit is a ReactJS based component library developed for Afiniti. Airokit was built using ReactJS, SCSS, Custom Grid System, Responsive Design, White/Dark Theme, Rollup, Storybook, Jest, Custom NPM Proxy and some third-party applications. Airokit consists of every User Interface Component required to develop a User Interface. Used Docker to deploy Storybook and published to Afiniti's custom proxy.

## 04. THE SEEK

The Seek is a Machine Learning based CCTV Surveillance System, developed this project using ReactJS, SCSS, Ant Design, Python, Python Flask, PyMongo, NumPy, Tensor-flow, Keras, Open-CV and Nvidia CUDA. This project captures CCTV Feed using Device IP Address, runs an activity and an object detection model to detect suspicious activity, weapons and notify administration. The suspicious part is also recorded and stored for admin to review or use later. Demo can be provided upon request.

#### **05. VOGUE JUNCTION**

Vogue Junction is one of my own projects. The idea behind vogue junction is to combine the functionalities of an e-commerce site with the likes of YouTube, Instagram and Medium. Specially designed for Fashion Freelancers to showcase and sell their work exclusively. This site was developed using ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, MongoDB and purely custom designed theme in SCSS.

#### 06. OVERSIGHT

Oversight is a monitoring system developed to monitor statistics RAM Usage, CPU Utilization, AI Utilization, Disk Utilization and much more performance related statistics. The first version was developed using ReactJS, Redux, SCSS, NodeJS, MongoDB, Redis, the second version was developed using the same UI as version one but with Golang at the server side, the third and final version was built using JAVA, Spring boot, SNMP and MongoDB.

## **07. OVERSIGHT SIGNALS MANAGER**

Oversight Signals Manager (OSM) is a signal management system that organizes and provides the ability to Create, Read, Update and Delete configurations for each sensor used in Oversight such as performance statistics i.e., CPU Utilization. OSM was developed using ReactJS, Apollo Client, Ant Design, SCSS, UseForm, Hasura, GraphQL and PostgreSQL.



# **HONOURS & AWARDS**

# **EXCELLENT PERFORMANCE**

AFINITI

Certificate for excellent performance and commendable work during first year of my services.

## **EXCEPTIONAL WORK**

IVY ALUMNI

Certificate of appreciation presented for exceptional work in developing next generation AI Solutions at Afiniti, a venture of Columbia and IVY Alum Zia Chishti.